How do you feel about the fact that Russia
Как ты относишься к тому что Россия
attacked
напала на
Ukraine normally and calmly? So it’s
Украину нормально спокойно Значит так
necessary. Well, in the sense that it’s
надо Ну в смысле так
necessary, we don’t decide what happens in
надо не мы же решаем что происходит в
our country and in yours, there are people higher up who are
нашей и в вашей стране есть люди выше
probably more literate and
которые наверное по грамотнее и пооб
qualified, they know what will happen there next
зова нее они знают что там дальше будет
Hello,
происходить Здравствуйте
good time of day, where are you
доброе времени суток Вы
from? From Ryazan, Ryazan Yes, my dad
откуда С Рязани Рязань Да у меня батя
once served there as a waterman. Moreover, during the Soviet Union,
когда-то водо Да ещё При Советском Союзе
137th. Well, I don’t know the
137 по Ну я не знаю
number, military, it doesn’t
номер
matter, I myself have the number,
военно неважно я сам номер есть
military air force, military air
военно-воздушная во военно-воздушный
space Denny, there would be
космический Денни бы
units A  are you in Ryazan itself or are you
части есть А вы в самой Рязани или вы
somewhere in the Ryazan
где-то в Рязанской
region? I’m in Ryazan and I served in the
области Я в Рязани и вот служил воен
air military and space military. Well, now
воздушных воен космических вос Ну сейчас
you are because I see that the
вы находитесь потому что я смотрю что
design is clearly not Ryazan,
дизайн какой-то явно не Рязанский
some kind of rustic design And this is a barn
какой-то деревенский дизайн А это сарай
I’m at my grandmother’s  Why are you in the barn and at
Я у бабушки А что вы в сарае и у
grandma’s? Where should I rest now
бабушки А где мне сейчас
except at grandma’s except in the barn? It’s
кроме как у бабушки кроме как в сарае
interesting. No, not against the backdrop of the flag.
интересно Не ну не на фоне же флага
I think you’ll agree. Well, yes, I
отдыхать Я думаю согласитесь Ну да
agree, it’s better in the barn than against the backdrop of the flag. And
согласен лучше в сарае чем на фоне флага
you came to grandma?  to a
А это ты к бабушке приехал в
village to which village is not in
деревню в какую деревню нет в самой
Ryazan itself? This grandmother lives in Ryazan.
Рязани Это бабушка живёт са Рязани
Grandma understood the question well. Why do you?
бабушка понял хорошо вопрос А почему вы
That is, you live in Ryazan and your
То есть вы живёте в Рязани и ваша
grandmother is in Ryazan and you went to
бабушка в Рязани и вы к ней пошли
sit with her and
посидеть у неё вра
drink alcohol, probably logical
выпить алкоголь наверное логично потому
because for example, I have  I have difficulties at home
что у меня например дома трудности
because my parents also swear at me
потому что и родители мне ругаются по
about this, so I came here
этому поводу поэтому я пошёл сюда потому
because I have more contact with my grandmother.
что с бабушкой я больше контактируют пщ
That’s why I’m here, that’s all, that
относится Поэтому я здесь вот и всё то
is, in Ryazan you can drink alcohol except
есть в Рязани выпить алкоголь кроме как
in your grandmother’s barn,
в сарае у бабушки
there’s nowhere you can drink it in the entrance
негде не можно в подъезде можно е выпить
somewhere to have a drink and there are no more establishments there are no
где-нибудь выпить а больше заведений
more, in short, you
никаких нет всё больше нет короче бухать
need to drink hard It’s necessary either at grandma’s or on a
Нужно трушно либо у бабушки либо на
bench or in the park, I
лавочке либо в парке всё всё
understood everything correctly, well, and I understand that it’s
верно понял хорошо а я так понимаю что у
cold in your barn Yes, because you’re
тебя в сарае холодно Да потому что ты
sitting dressed in two
сидишь одетый в две
jackets A  you see the guy also and steam sales
курточки А ты парня видишь ещ и пар даж
I see Parda And your grandmother’s barn is not
вижу Парда А у вас сарай у бабушки не
heated
отапливается
final second Tap And how old are you
конечном вторая Тап А сколько Вам лет
I’m 43 you are how old 28 28 who
вот мне 43 вам сколько 28 28 кем
do you work for train operator who is the
работаете тель поездов кто составитель
train compiler Yeah trains like you make up yes
поездов Ага составы типа составляете да
140 if you ask for
140 если ты спросишь
salary salary 140  Why won’t
зарплату зарплата 140 Почему не буде
you rest? Why don’t you have enough
отдыхать Почему тебе не не хватает
salary? I have enough, I save everywhere
зарплаты Мне хватает экономлю везде мне
for all these establishments. I’d rather
на все вот эти вот заведения Я лучше
sit with the women, but what do you do with 140,000 -
посижу у баб а куда ты девает 140.000 -
that’s 1,400 dollars?
это 1400 долларов Куда ты
yours in yours to me My parents gave it to me, it’s
своей в своей мне Родители подарили она
not mine, well, according to the documents, it’s mine to me, my
не моя ну по документам она моя мне
parents gave me an apartment, I live alone in an
родители подарили квартиру я живу один в
apartment, Yeah, and you want to
квартире Угу И ты хочешь ещё одну
buy another apartment, right for renting.
квартиру купить правильно под съём съём
Dear, we rent it out so that we can help you.
Дорогой у нас сдавать чтобы ба пом ВС
Ponya is married
Поня женат
Was not, has a girlfriend
Был Не был девушка
no, the girl
есть нет девушка
was an interrogation, well,
была допрос ну
interesting Come on,
интересно Дава давай вы
come on, come on
давай давай Ты что капу
You were a girl You,
гн была девушка У тебя
of course, had a lot of money for them, it takes a
конечно много было на них уходит очень
lot of money, to be honest, how many years
много денег если честно сколько лет
ago did you have a girl?
назад была девушка У
A month
тебя месяц
ago, in short, he extracted your entire salary from you
назад короче вытянул из тебя всю
and you left her Yes  not about him I didn’t
зарплату и ты её бросил Да не о неме Не
pull it out, but too much is spent on
вытягивал но слишком много тратится на
all sorts of gadgets for her car that
всякие приблуды для её машины которые
I don’t need, even if he’s ugly Money
мне не нужны пускай он она уроди Деньги
Bert spare parts for this
Берт запчасти для этой
Masha in the cops, I’ll put the money aside and buy myself
Маши в копе э деньги отложу и куплю себе
another new car later than invest it
потом другую новую машину чем вкладывать
in some old bucket Well  it also works out there
в какое-то старое ведро Ну ещё туда
when with a girl it’s time to
получается когда с девушкой вре
overpay money with a girl you meet
переплата денег с девушкой встречаешься
with her, I don’t get drunk in the garage, you already need to
с ней не побухаю в гараже её уже нужно
take her somewhere to a cafe And this is already
куда-то в кафе сводить А это уже
money, a
деньга
good good scheme like yes, I understand, but you
хорошая хорошая схема типа да понял а
help your grandmother
бабушке помогаешь
with money, no, I help I help
деньгами нет помогаю Я помогаю
her No, if she what  she’ll ask, she
ей Нет если она что-то спросит Она
never asks anything, I asked
никогда не спрашивает ничего я спрашивал
you, there’s enough and enough like that, not
тебе хватает и хватает вот так не
with money, I’m everywhere on the territory on her
деньгами я везде на территории на её
site, everywhere to everyone. I’ll help as much as I can, and
участке везде всем Я помогу чем смогу а
grandma grandma helps you there, already
бабушка бабушка тебе помогает там уже
there for your birthday, gives you money there for the
там на день рождения даёт деньги там на
New Year,
Новый год тебе
gifts for you.  this has never happened Well, a
подарки такого никогда не было Ну
gift, yes a gift, of course She gives
подарок да подарок конечно Всем дарит
gifts to everyone, she gives gifts for her birthday
подарки она дарит подарки вот на день
How do you feel about the fact that Russia
Как ты относишься к тому что Россия
attacked
напала на
Ukraine normally and calmly So that’s how it
Украину нормально спокойно Значит так
should be I mean, that’s how it
надо В смысле так
should be, we don’t decide what happens in
надо не мы же решаем что происходит в
our and your country  there are people higher up
нашей и в вашей стране есть люди выше
who are probably more educated
которые наверно погра мотней
and pooo they know that what will
и пооо они знают что там даль будет
happen there in the future is not Yes, what will happen in the first
происходить там не Да что сде в первую
place in the WTO line So it had to be
очеред ВТО очере Значит так нужно было
done That is, if these people, if these
сделать То есть если эти люди если эти
people send you to die in another country,
люди тебя пошлют умирать в другую страну
you will just go because  they are smarter
Ты просто пойдёшь потому что они умнее
Yes, I won’t
Да так я не
go, so I’ll take you and
пойду как вот возьму тебя и пойдёшь я не
you’ll go, I won’t go, but I won’t go, but they’ll
пойду а не я-то не пойду так а вот
announce mobilization and you’ll go,
объявят мобилизацию и пойдёшь
so there was a mobilization, I didn’t go Well, the
так была мобилизация я-то не пошёл Ну
next one will continue to announce Yes,
вот следующий объявит продолжат Да
you’ll go
пойдёшь
and I won’t go to the next one
и на следующую не
what car do you have
пойду машина у тебя какая
prora Lada Lada Lada How much does it
prora Лада Лада Лада Сколько
cost in 2013 now 500 bought what
стоит 2013 год сейчас 500 покупал что
I bought now for 300 now it costs
сейчас покупал за 300 сейчас она стоит
500 bought and bought 300,000 rubles and
уже 500 покупал а покупал 300.000 руб а
now it costs it back for 300 bought
сейчас стоит Она наза за 300 покупал
now it can be sold for 500 but it
сейчас е можно продать за 500 года о она
has increased in price  like, that is, you still have 200,000
выросла в цене типа то есть ты ещ 200000
rubles to heat up on it And why heat up I
руб нагре на ней А на чём нагре я другую
won’t normally buy another car all the cars
машину нормально не куплю все машины
have also skyrocketed in price, others not only the
тоже взлетели в цене другие не только
Priora has skyrocketed, everyone has gone up in price Lada Priora turns out it
Приора взлетел все влетели Лада Приора
costs $5,000 now
получается 5000 долларов сейчас стоит
Well, it’s a pretty decent car, that means the car I don’t
Ну довольно приличная значит машина я не
know I don’t  drove it
знаю я не ездил
turns out, well, not everyone Look, not every
получается ну не каждый Смотри не каждый
American can afford to
американец себе может позволить Ладу
buy a Lada Priora Well, that’s cool Everyone, everyone
Приору купить Ну это круто Каждый каждый
has a salary Well, like the thirteenth year, the
у них зарплата Ну как тринадцатого года
Priora is only 9 years old Priora Well, this is
Приора это всего 9 лет Приоре Ну это
quite a
довольно
major 9 years old Priora is a car, all of it
[__] 9 лет Приоре это машина всё её в
should be thrown into scrap because  this is a Lada,
утиль надо выкинуть потому что это Лада
first of all, a Lada always rots, my
это во-первых Лада всегда гниёт у меня
car is already rotting in the second round. Well, in the first
машина уже по второму Ну по первому
round, the factory was painted; in the
кругу крашена завод была крашена по
second round, everything was painted from me,
второму кругу от меня была крашена
so why don’t you buy yourself a new
всё так а что ты не купишь себе новую
car for a million rubles?
машину за по милна руб
Why should I buy for half  milna
ла Зачем мне покупать за пол милна
rubles a new car if I have
рублей новую машину если у меня есть
a car that I have in I didn’t sell it bought
вока которая у меня во я е продал купил
another everything what’s the problem can Kato
другую всё в чём проблема может Като
nogo Japanese drink I don’t see the point of
ного японца пить Я не вижу смыс
transferring such a lot of money to a
переводить такие большие деньги на
car that just carries You
машину которая Те просто возит Тебе
Kopeyka can take you from point to
может и Копейка отвезти от точки до
point  Why do you need a machine at all, why
точки Зачем нужна вообще машина для чего
to transfer you from point to
чтобы перевести тебя от точки до точки
destination correctly? Yes, there may be
назначения правильно Да там Может
something else to transfer potatoes. Well,
картошку перевести ещё что-то Ну
look, the task of a machine is not just to transfer
смотри задача машины не просто перевести
you from point A to point b, but to transfer from a to
тебя с точки А в точку б а перевести с а
transfer with a certain level of
перевести с определённым уровнем
Comfort and a certain level
Комфорта и определённым уровнем
safety
безопасности
and
и
Safety of the car uh Lada prora
Безопасность машины ээ Lada prora
how
насколько
safe is four airbags
безопасная четыре подушки безопасности у
I had a Luxury
меня был Люкс
package, it’s cool Luxury
комплектация прикольно Люкс
straight Luxury I sold it
прямо Люкс я её продал
later, it’s cool I’m saying why four
потом прикольно Я говорю почему четыре
because all four worked, I myself,
потому что все четыре сработали я сам
that’s why there were four, well, there were four
вот поэтому и четыре ну четыре было
now, they probably aren’t there anymore
сейчас уже наверное уже нет
just stubs stand How do you
их просто заглушки стоят Как как ты
think who is to blame for the fact that Russia
считаешь кто виноват в том что Россия
is at war with
воюет с
Ukraine Russia is at war with Ukraine Who is to
Украиной Россия воюет с Украиной Кто
blame There are no guilty How there are no to
виноват виноватых нет Как виноватых
blame Well, there is no one to blame so who
нет Ну нет виноватых надо так кто на
attacked whom who
напал кто на кого
attacked whom You are asking me a question Yes,
напал ты у меня вопрос спрашиваешь да
what do you think  Well, it’s provocative, I’m
а ты как думаешь нуже провокационно я же
asking you, well, this is a provocative
у тебя спрашиваю ну это провокационный
question Yes, I’m a
вопрос Да я
provocateur, I
провокатор я
see. Okay, let’s attack you and
вижу Хорошо давай мы напали на вас и что
what if you attacked, you’re guilty, it
так то если вы напали Вы же виноваты
turns out why he should be and
получается почему он должен быть а
why did he attack at all, you know, no, I don’t
почему он вообще напали знаете нет не
know,
знаю
explain,
объясни
think about it, I didn’t  I know, I’ve been trying to
подумай я не знаю я вот пытаюсь
figure it out for how many years now and it’s not
разобраться уже сколько лет не
working.
получается Объясни
Explain to me, probably only one person here
мне наверное тут объясни только один
who doesn’t know, your Supreme
кто не знаю ваш Верховный
Commander-in-Chief understands, listen, there is
главнокомандующий понял слушай есть
such a proposal, look, I’m
такое предложение вот смотри я тут
running a small chat here. Yes, people
небольшой чатик веду Да меня люди
look at me against singing their questions.
смотрят против поть их вопро Бут
I’ll ask you questions.
задавать вопросы я тебе буду
voice Let's try Let's
озвучивать Давай попробуем Давай Тебя
What's your name Vlad Vlad so me Andryukha so
как зовут Влад Влад так меня Андрюха так
People Let's write questions to
Народ Давайте пишем вопросы
Vlad Vlad from Ryazan train compiler
Владу Влад из Рязани составитель
140 that 140 salary 140 kilograms
140 что 140 зарплата 140 килограмм
will arrive Let's ask Vlad questions
прилетит Давайте вопросы Владу
Oxy asks What is
Окси спрашивает Какая пенсия у
grandma's pension grandma's pension 20,000 20,000
бабушки пенсия у бабушки 20.000 20.000
so olana he's 28 years old
так олана ему 28 лет
so
так
so this one asks how much will you drink today
так сей спрашивает сколько ты сегодня
how much will you drink I can answer this question
сколько выпьешь на этот вопрос я могу
visually let’s say
ответить визуально скажем так
we don’t have beer and vodka yet I understand Yulia
не у нас ещё пивко и водочка понял Юлия
asks Or were the relay cabinets burning on your railway
спрашивает Или горели у вас на железной
that the relay cabinets I’m not an
шкафы что релейные шкафы не я не
electrician I’m not an
электрик я не
electrician were burning and setting fire  if you had
электрик горели и поджигали ли у вас на
something like that on the railway Doro, wouldn’t our cars be
железный Доро такого не бы у нас вагоны
on fire, woe is it, only the
горели вот горе только
cars Goli the cars were on fire. Cool, yes,
вагоны Голи вагоны горели Прикольно да
Gottman asks How is the signal given with
готман спрашивает Как подаётся сигнал
the flag forward and
флажком вперёд и
quieter the signal with the flag and quieter
тише сигнал с флажком и тише
yes, I didn’t understand something, you can do it,
да я что-то не понял ты можешь его это
can he do it for you  the government man will answer a little differently, the government
может он тебе чучуть ответит по-другому
man will answer a little differently, the
госман чуть ответь по-другому
government Leonid asks how you managed to make
гос Леонид спрашивает как вы умудрились
the whole country go crazy. We are trying to go crazy
всей страной Сойти с
for the sake of the whole people. How much does beer
ради лага па всего народа Сколько в
cost in Russia,
России стоит
depending on what beer you can buy beer
пиво смотря какое пиво пиво можно купить
and for 37 rubles you can for 50 for 60 for 70  for
и за 37 руб можно за 50 за 60 за 70 за
80 for 100 for 200 for 300 for 400 for
80 за 100 за 200 за 300 за 400 за
500 basically the average price tag is
500 в основном средний ценник
rubles
рублей
Okay,
Окей
so they ask grandma, will you call your grandmother,
так спрашивают бабушку позовёшь
no Yes, she is resting, she is sleeping, and I understand for the old ones,
нет Да она отдыхает она спит и на старые
let’s honor Uva to
понял дадим честь Ува
the elders, the kindergartener. The question is, is it
старшим э садивник Спрашивается ране
heated? How is grandma’s house
отапливается А бабушкин дом как
heated? gas heating
отапливается газовое отопление
gas  heating,
газовое отопление
so if you had the opportunity to
так если бы у тебя была возможность
get another citizenship, which one would you
получить другое гражданство какое бы ты
choose
выбрал
I don’t even know. By the way, I haven’t thought
даже не знаю Я кстати не задумался
about this
насчёт этого
question. Turn off there Turn off the music so that
вопроса Выключи там Выключи музон чтобы
it doesn’t
он нам не
bother us, so there’s also Maloy and Ponya Oh, let’s
мешал так там ещё Малой а Поня О давай
show it to a comrade. Hello. Show
товарищу Привет покажем Покажи
comrade, comrade doesn’t want to.  show on
товарищ товарищ не хочет показывать на
camera that's why I'm alone
камеру поэтому я один
so if it was possible to change
так если бы была возможность поменять
Putin
Путина поменял
would I change no
бы нет
Ivan asks how many times
Иван спрашивает сколько раз от пола
can you
можешь
do push-ups from the floor 100
отжаться 100
minimum they ask for a toilet in the street or a
минимум спрашивают туалет в на улице или
toilet in grandma's house a toilet on the street
туалет в доме у бабушки туалет на улице
in my house a toilet in the house understood
у меня дома туалет в доме понял
Goman Gosman asks  like on the
Гоман госман спрашивает как на железной
railway a signal is given forward and
дороге подаётся сигнал вперёд и
quietly forward forward with your hand you wave back
тише вперёд вперёд рукой махаешь назад
down the brake Kosma understood me or not the go
вниз тормоз Косма понял меня или нет го
signal I understand Let’s continue
чный сигнал Понятно Давай дальше
like this Olena asks why are you sure
так Олена спрашивает почему ты уверен
that they didn’t
что не
set fire so I have a delay
подпалили так у меня отсрочка
from
от
So I have a reservation reservation Renata asks
Так у меня бронь бронь Рената спрашивает
what the  the ring is on your
что за кольцо у тебя на
hand save
руке спаси сохрани
save Save and save yes Are you
Спаси и сохрани да А ты боишься
probably afraid of the Chechens Yes they are
чеченцев наверное Да они
kind of
какие-то
scary More likely yes than
страшные Скорее да чем
no Let’s ask more questions like a
нет Давайте ещё вопросы так
believer
верующий
believer we have some kind of opinion poll that went
верующий у нас какой-то соцопрос пошёл
straight specifically Yes
прямо конкретно Да
love they ask Kobzon’s favorite song
люби спрашивают любимая песня Кобзона
[music]
[музыка]
Which Kobzon I don’t even listen to the dog I don’t know
Какая Кобзон не слушаю даже пес не знаю
why he’s wearing a jacket He’s in the barn drinking
почему он в куртке Он же в сарае бухает
with a friend at his grandmother’s [ __ ] so so coldly
с другом у бабушки в сра так так холодно
Bartholomew asks the Ukrainians
спрашивает Варфоломей украинцев
you’re afraid of the
боишься
Ukrainians you can be afraid of the Russians depending on
украинцев можно и русских бояться смотря
who
кого
[music]
[музыка]
Uh-huh So where’s it better to go to prison or to your own
Угу Так куда лучше в тюрьму или на сво
Question  good by the way
Вопрос хороший кстати
for
за
Naso
насо
so a glass of vodka in one gulp you will drink
так стакан водки залпом выпьешь
vodka in one gulp I don’t have a glass but I can
водки залпом у меня рюмки нет но могу
have a drink Yeah I have one
выпить Угу есть
asks Arato do you support Hamas or
спрашивает арато поддерживаешь Хамас или
Israel In this history I am not in any way
Израиль Я в истории в этой ни в какой не
for Kamaz or for Israel I
являюсь за Камаз ни за Израиль Я в Росси
live my quiet life in Russia all the time
живу своей спокойной жизни всё
Banderaites are
рабо бандеровцев
afraid of our defect, our Bandera was
боишься наша недоработка наша Бандера
more and more afraid of that.
всё больше боялся
It’s clear,
Понятно так
so if you go to your place and they kill you there,
так если ты пойдёшь на сво и тебя там
why do you die
убьют за что ты получается погибнешь
in fact for
по факту ни за
nothing? What kind of education do you have, a
что Какое образование у тебя сре
special
специальный
lawyer, an
юрист юрист
average special lawyer, not a higher education specialist, I
средний специальный юрист не высший сред
understand And you  Why did you, after
специальный понял И ты А почему ты после
law school, become a train sorter,
юридического пошёл сортировщика поездов
not a sorter, but a train compiler, a
не сортировщика а составителем поездов
train compiler,
составителем поездов
yes? Because the salary is good, that’s why you
да Потому что зарплата хорошая поэтому
went there. And why in Russia does a lawyer have a
туда пошёл А почему в России у юриста
bad
плохая
salary in my city where I live?
зарплата именно в моём городе где я живу
Okay, if I explain it to you like this, I
Ладно если тебе так
need to work as a lawyer in
объяснить мне надо юристом работать в
Moscow in order to  get good money
Москве чтобы получать хорошие бабки
so that I can work in Moscow I need to
чтобы я работал в Москве мне надо
rent an apartment, an apartment there costs
снимать квартиру квартира там стоит
at least 60 rubles to rent an apartment for a month And
минимум 60 руб снять квартиру на месяц А
how much will I receive initially? Okay,
сколько я буду получать изначально Ладно
I can live with my relatives and live there for
я могу у родственников пожить да там
a month or two, then they’ll say go, like,
месяц-два потом они скажут пошёл типа ну
well, where’s the guy?  you can do it and that’s it. And
кенту се сам там как сможешь и всё А
their salary, I won’t say that it’s
зарплата у них я не скажу чтобы какая-то
very good. Yes, in Moscow it might be
очень сильно хорошая Да в Москве может и
good, but in other cities from
хорошая вот в другом в других городах от
Moscow and further away, the salary is
Москвы и подальше там зарплата уже
completely different, so I went to my
совсем другая поэтому я пошёл в своём
hometown and that’s it. How much do they have?  you in
родном городе и всё А сколько у вас в
Ryazan lie and good work and salary
Рязани льё и хорошая работа и зарплата
How much in Ryazan does a lawyer get
Сколько сколько в Рязане юрист получает
a little money Well, approximately how much? A
денег немного Ну сколько приблизительно
friend of mine works 80,000 he
У меня знакомый работает 80.000 он
gets paid like that
получает так
lawyer I don’t
юрист мне профессии не
like the profession let’s start with this I should have started
нравится начнём с этого надо было начать
I’m coming now
иду сейчас
[music]
[музыка]
second Come on Dima That’s what I’m saying  talk
секунду Давай Дима Вот я что говор
so
так
now So So
сечас Так Так
So what is the point of Russia
Так в чём смысл России
asking among the people probably in strength strength
спрашивать в народе наверное в силе силе
among the people And what is the strength of the
в народе А в чём сила
people in
народа в
Vera And at the World Cup Vera watch the film watched
Вере А в ЧМ Вера смотре фильм смотрел в
what is the strength
чём сила
brother In the World Cup Si Well okay [ __ ] that’s not right Well
брат В ЧМ Си Ну ладно Бля не впра вот Ну
in the World Cup this is strength in the people, strength and everything is in the
это в ЧМ сила в народе сила и всё в
believing people. And what do you believe in, the people,
верующего народе А в что ты веришь народ
the strength of
сила
PTO, the strength if the people are with you, they
ВОМ сила если с тобой народ он в тебя
believe in you, this is already your strength, you
верит это уже твоя сила тебе больше
don’t need anything else, it’s
ничего не нужно
cool, what do you believe in, what do you
прикольно в что ты веришь во что ты
believe in, I believe in  God and more and more no one else
веришь я верю в Бога и всё больше никого
seems to me to believe Poa How what is your
Мне кажется не верит Поа Как как твоего
God's name name Jesus Christ understood the 10
Бога зовут имя Иисус Христос понял 10
commandments you
заповедей
know Well my mother says teach me but I
знаешь Ну мне мать говорит учи но я
say something I say teach you
что-то я говорю ка учи ты
what maybe yes I’m young and stupid I don’t
что может быть да я молодой и глупый не
know but you know
знаю а ты знаешь
no num No, you're not young, I'm not a
не нум Не ну ты ты не молодой тебе я не
believer I'm not a believer I'm
верующий я не верующий я неверующий
not a believer of Christ I'm not a believer
Христа я неверующий ты неверующий ты не
young and stupid, I’ll
говорил что ты молодой и глупый я тебе
tell you, you’re not young, you’re 28 years old, you’re
скажу Ты не молодой тебе 28 лет это уже
not
не
young anymore, you’re already quite mature,
молодой ты уже довольно зрелый разуму
you want to teach reason, or I’m not just saying that.
хочешь научить или не просто говорю так
In which countries was he asking and not Yanga
В каких странах был спрашивает а не Янга
in Russia? Wasn’t anywhere else at sea
в России был Больше нигде не был на море
at home in Russia naha  I understand why it
у себ в России наха Поня А почему не
wasn’t in other
было в других
countries because I don’t know because
странах потому что не знаю потому что
we probably didn’t have enough money,
нас наверное денег может не хватало
maybe there was something else I
может ещё что-то не хватало
was missing. For example, I couldn’t go to other
мя была Например я не мог в другие
countries and they ask why people in all
страны спрашивают Почему люди в во всех
countries are interested in politics, they are not
странах интересуются политикой они не
interested in this  question I can’t
интересуются на этот вопрос я не могу
answer why they aren’t interested all
ответить почему они не интересуются все
people are different some are interested
люди по-разному кто-то интересуется
some are not interested I for example hear
кто-то не интересуется Я например слышу
from the news and I hear Well, how would we
из новости и слышу Ну и как бы это
get through this
проехали
That’s how someone treats someone doesn’t
Вот так кто-то относится кто-то не
and all people  different everything is
относится и все люди разные все по
different Yulia asks how you see
разному Юлия спрашивает каким ты видишь
your future in Russia in 10
своё будущее в России через 10
years in 10 years in 10 years I want to buy myself in
лет через 10 лет себе хочу купить
10 years how much for how much is the apartment
чере 10 лет сколько на сколько квартира
now waiting wait I can
сейчас подо подожди могу
earn buy three apartments rent out buy
заработать купить три квартиры сдавать в
cars rent out
аренду купить машины сдавать в
and work the same  everything to my work
аренду и работать так же на своей работе
I understood it all correctly, look in
всё Я правильно понял это всё смотри за
10 years, three apartments - that’s an apartment in
10 лет три квартиры - это по квартире в
years and
года да
how much your
сколько у вас квартира
apartment costs depends on what kind of apartment
стоит смотря кака Какую квартиру хочешь
you want to buy Kata, which one do you want? Well, the one you
купить Кату какую ты хо Ну ту какую ты
want to buy, how much it
хочешь купить сколько она
costs, look, let’s open it like this
стоит смотри давай так Открой
calculator now together media let's
калькулятор сейчас вместе СМИ посчитаем
calculate Yes, I'll do the math in my head Come on, let's
Да я в голове посчитаю Давай давай
calculate the apartment for 2 mil so that's it for
посчитаешь квартира шка по-2 милна так
you Ren is a little bit better, a little bit,
тебе Рен есть чучуть получше чуть-чуть
but there won't be a good repair there, that's in
но там не будет хорошего ремонта это в
any case, you'll have to redo everything anyway
любом случае тебе в любом случае на всё
or  leave also Therefore,
переделать или оставлять также Поэтому
it’s better to buy cheaper, that’s right Yes,
лучше купить подешевле правильно Да
logically, and make repairs there for
логически и сделать там ремонт за
500,000 for 2 lyama Well, okay, she
500.000 за 2 ляма Ну ладно она тебя
got you a house in 2 lyama Yes, and you rent for
встала хата в 2 ляма Да и ты сдаёшь за
60,000 a month and everything is money for you
60.000 в месяц и всё тебе бабки
slowly stop stop stop you said
потихоньку ка стоп стоп стоп ты говорил
60,000 a month this  rent in Moscow And
60.000 в месяц это в Москве аренда А у
in Ryazan, where do you get
вас в Рязане откуда
these from, wait, wait,
такие стой стой
Open Avita Do you have Avita?
стой Открой Авита У тебя есть Авита
Open Avito, no, well, you now have
Открой Авито нету ну у тебя сейчас есть
several taps Look Open Avito,
несколько кранов Посмотри Открой Авито
look at renting apartments in Moscow, how much does it
посмотри аренда квартир в Москве сколько
cost in Moscow? I won’t even tell you about the
в Москве стоит Я тебе даже про
Moscow region. How much in  It
Подмосковье вообще молчу Сколько в
costs to rent an apartment in Moscow Look,
Москве стоит аренда квартиры Ты посмотри
I’m banned from Avito, it won’t let me in, you
я у меня забанена Авито не пускает ты
tell me that there
скажи та там там
prices are there, I’ll say more there, not 60,000, it’s
цены это больше скажу там не 60.000 это
not in Moscow 60 60,000
не в Москве 60 60.000
Moscow There you open Avido Look
Москве Там ты открой авидо Посмотри
how much it costs for a one-room apartment on Vykhina
сколько стоит однушка на выхина
somewhere or somewhere else
где-нибудь или ещё где-нибудь
look, in short, in Ryazan, you
посмотри короче в Рязани у вас типа
can buy an apartment for 20,000 for 2 million
квартиру можно купить за 20.000 за 2 млн
Yes, with the renovation you already get
Да с ремонтом уже получается
OBD, yes, well, it’s you Ho,
ОБД ты покупаешь да Ну это же ты Хо это
that’s not
по это не
the price, it’s 20,000 dollars, so you
цен это 20.000 долларов так а сдавать ты
’ll rent it out for min rubles, the repairs will be from a
её будешь за мин руб ремонтом будет у а
you'll rent it out for
сдавать ты её будешь за
$60,600, then you put it there,
60 600 долларов потом туда сажаешь
look, look, the main thing is not to
смотри смотри Главное чтобы не
drink, drink, you know, watched this
бухали бухают васеля знаешь смотрел этот
Univer Univer Old dorm, new dorm,
Универ Универ Старая общага новая общага
well, I went on TNT Well, I went to Russia
ну вот по ТНТ шёл А ну в России шёл
Sorry And this, well, there
Извини И это ну и вот там тоже там уже
was already this one there too  what's his
был этот как его
name the guy says he evicted everything is the
зовут чувак говорит высел все дела так
same and I'll buy an apartment there's something I don't
же и я куплю квартиру что-то не
like the neighbors had a fight I don't argue
понравится соседи поругались Да не спорю
with the neighbors I have to keep everything in order from bottom to top right
с соседями надо все лады держать снизу
left everywhere Absolutely
сверху справа слева везде Абсолютно во
settled in with Uzbeks Uzbeks it's even better to
заселил узбеков узбеков даже лучше
move in Why Because the Uzbeks don't
заселить Почему Потому что узбеки не
yell anything  Yes, they are there for the whole house
орут ничего Да они там всю хату
and the repairs will come out cheaper later for 50,000,
те ремонт дешевле выйдет потом на 50.000
spent both
потратил обой
my calculator and immediately calculated if you
мой калькулятор сразу посчитал если ты
buy a house for 2 million for 2 million and
покупаешь хату за 2 млн за 2 млн А
you rent it out for 60,000, you bought it for 20,000
сдаёшь по 60.000 это ж за 20.000 купил
dollars and for 6,600 dollars a month
долларов а за 6 600 долларов в месяц
you give it for a year 60  wait, wait, I'll
даёшь это за год 60 стой стой я тебя
interrupt you, it turns out to be less than
перебью там получается меньше
sixty, it turns out because there is also a
шестидесяти выходит потому что там ещё
communal apartment, a communal apartment. Who pays
коммуналка коммуналку Кто платит
the owner, pays for the communal apartment? Well, in short,
владелец платит коммуналку Да короче по
50 50 somewhere, maybe
50 50 где-то может
500 dollars net year, that's you
500 долларов чистыми го год это тебя
smart 12 it's you, 6000 dollars
умном 12 это у тебя 6000 долларов
net it turns out that for every year
чистыми получается что за каждый го
every
каждый
year PP you get that with this
год ПП у тебя получается что с таким
situation in 3 years you
раскладом за 3 года ты
pay off, this is kind of
окупается это какая-то
too much Well, it seems to me that this is
слишком Ну мне кажется это
not possible, this is not reasonable Why did you say in 3
нере это нере й А почему ты сказал за 3
years I will buy an apartment because I
года я куплю квартиру потому что я
look, I multiplied 3 by 6,000 and
смотри я я умножил 3 на 6.000 и
it turned out  18,000 dollars This is your
получилось 18.000 долларов Вот это твоя
twenty Yes, look Rick, we have net per
двадцатка Да смотри Рик чистыми у нас в
month how many months do we have 12 months
месяц сколько у нас месяцев 12 месяцев
600,000 per year Well, that’s 600,000 per year for Well
600.000 в год Ну вот 600.000 в год за Ну
5,000 look 50,000 for 12 it will be
5.000 смотри 50.000 у на 12 это будет
600 50 for 12 it will be 600 600,000 Yes for
600 50 у 12 это будет 600 600.000 Да за
3 years  this is 600 y for 3 this is 1.800 that’s
3 года это 600 у на 3 это 1.800 вот
almost 2 lyama already in 3 years it has been repaid
почти 2 ляма уже за 3 года отбилась это
too quickly in 3 years This house
слишком быстро за 3 года Эта хата
will be repaid
отобьёмся
no there is nowhere such houses that
нету нету нигде таких хат которые
are repaid in 3 years otherwise this market
отбиваются за 3 года иначе бы Этот рынок
Yes, it would be easy to
Да просто бы
generate myself I’m a realtor I’m just
генерированию сам я риэлтор как раз я
selling
продаю
apartments neho skame 18 years of practice
квартиры нехо скаме 18 лет практика у
I have 18 years of practice in 2 years it will be
меня 18 лет практики через 2 года будет
unrealistic there are no such people either in Ukraine or
дто нереально нету таких ни в Украине ни
in Russia so that in 3 years you can recapture
в России чтобы за 3 года ты отбил хату
the rent of the house, otherwise
аренд иначе
the rent will be compressed And I’m passing through here, don’t look, I wo
аренда сжат А к нам проезжаю не смотри я
n’t rent to you again  for such a
тебе ещ раз никто бы не снимал за такую
price it’s
цену это
definitely Well, bring the charger to me,
однозначно Ну принеси Зарядку мне
it
он в натуре
will fit in kind It’s just that somehow you manage to
сядет Просто у тебя как-то получается
Ryazan for the price of an apartment, the prices
Рязань по цене на квартиру цены дешёвые
for an apartment are cheap and the rent is just crazy,
на квартиру а аренда прямо сумасшедшие
you somehow seem to me to be overbearing,
ты как-то мне кажется подзвякувати
so I think not you Look, I think
так вот Я думаю не вы Смотри Я я думаю
that I don’t need help from work I said
что работа мне помощь не нужна Я сказал
I don’t need anything I used my own car
мне ничего не нужно Я на Свою машину сам
to earn money for an apartment apartment Okay, I
заработал на квартиру квартира Ладно
live in my parents’ apartment I’m
квартира родителей на в ней живу Я
now buying myself another apartment,
сейчас покупаю себе другую квартиру
look, I’ve saved up I think that in your
смотри накопил Я думаю что в твоей
Ryazan for 60,000 rubles That is, for 600
Рязани за 60.000 руб То есть за 600
dollars  Yes, you can build an apartment together with
долларов Да можно вять квартиру вместе с
your grandmother’s hut with your grandmother’s paradise with
хатой твоей бабушки с раем бабушки с
your grandmother and you,
твоей бабушкой и тобой
what’s wrong with you for 600
что с тобой за 600
dollars,
долларов
what for 600 dollars, then Well, for 600
что что за 600 долларов то Ну за 600
dollars in Ryazan you can rent a hut,
долларов в Рязане можно взять снять хату
grandmother’s house, grandmother’s barn, grandmother,
бабушкин дом бабушкин сарай бабушку ещё
and
и
you will not be sold
тебя продадут
in  rent
не в аренду
and who and who Well, I agree, yes, who who will
и кто и кто Ну согласен да кто кто будет
pay for you and your grandmother for what?
платить за тебя с твоей бабушкой за что
Yes, I agree, the tenant sings on the same
Да согласен арендатор поёт в этот же
day and then my grandmother and I will live and
день а потом мы с бабушкой Будем жить и
everything is
всё
cool,
прикольно
agree that there my friend is already
согласен что там друган нервничает уже
a lot nervous Everyone
много Всех
doesn’t want to go  to show me the camera,
поро не хочет на камеру показываться мне
he brought a charger and Listen, look, I
принёс зарядку и Слушай ну смотри я
see that at this pace, at this pace,
смотрю что с таким темпом с таким темпом
firstly, you’re earning money. Yes, secondly,
во-первых ты зарабатываешь Да во-вторых
you have an apartment. I earn money, but I
есть у тебя квартира Я зарабатываю но я
don’t spend it. I’m saving, I’m saving up for
не трачу я экономлю я коплю себе на
an apartment, how many years have you been saving?  I do
квартиру да сколько лет ты уже копишь
n’t need anything on which I will
никакая не нужна на которую сейчас буду
spend money now no how many years have you
тратить бабок нет сколько лет ты уже
been saving for
копишь
an apartment then I don’t understand how much you are already
квартиру потом не понял сколько ты уже
saving for an apartment
собираешь на квартиру
no I want a house for 3 mil I have 700
не я хочу хату за 3 милна у меня 700
seis I’m just looking What’s wrong with your
сейс Просто я смотрю Что с твоей
salary and with such prices for an apartment
зарплатой и с такими ценами на квартиру
and  for rent you can already
и на аренды ты можешь за 10-15 лет уже
have 10 apartments in 10-15 years, you know, you
10 квартир иметь понимаешь это ж ты
buy an apartment and after 3 years
покупаешь квартиру а она через 3 года
the income doubles, she brings you a
приносит удваивается она приносит тебе
new apartment.
новую квартиру
Estimate, you say 10 apartments like I did,
Прикинь ты говоришь 10 квартир как я ла
after 3 years she makes another apartment,
через 3 года она делает ещ одну квартиру
that is, in  3 years you already have two
то есть через 3 года у тебя уже две
apartments Yes, even after 3 years I don’t understand
квартиры Да ещ через 3 года не понял
again Why two
опять Почему две
apartments of a year explain because from
квартиры года объясни потому что с
the rent from the
аренды с
rent of the first apartment 50 per month comes out of
аренды первой квартиры 50 в месяц идёт
what to take from the rent, we calculated
что с аренды брать то мы же посчитали
that in 3 years it will be 00 That is, for  3
Что за 3 года это будет 00 То есть за 3
years you buy one house That is,
года ты е одну хату покупаешь То есть
after 3 years you have two houses
через 3 года у тебя две хаты
ha they already bring two rents, that is,
ха они уже две аренды приносят то есть
after another 3 years That is, after 6 years
ещё через 3 года То есть через 6 лет У
You have four houses so And after 9 years,
тебя четыре хаты стаёт так А через 9 лет
that is, another plus 3 years eight  the hut will
то есть ещё плюс 3 года восемь хат будет
cost that much, it will cost even
столько стоить она будет стоить ещё
more, so you have to buy it Now while you
дороже поэтому надо покупать Сейчас пока
have the opportunity, then they will cost
возможность есть потом они будут стоить
Space, that is, look like this, for example, by 0
Космос то есть смотри так например к 0
years, by 0 years, you can, in short, have a million huts,
годам к 0 годам можно короче миллион хат
it doubles doubles,
иметь оно удваивается удваивается
in fact, the hut was for me, look, yes,
реально хата была чтобы у меня смотри да
in 12  years you have 16 huts through plut 15
через 12 лет у тебя 16 хат через плют 15
years old 32 huts 18 years old 64 huts 21 years old 128
лет 32 хаты 18 лет 64 хаты 21 год 128
huts Listen, in short, in general, you have one hut,
хат Слушай короче вообще тея одна хата у
you have one hut, what are you talking about, look,
тебя одна хата Ты о чём так она смотри
your hut is one, and that’s not even counting the fact
твоя хата одна и это ещё не считая того
that you’ll also bring in money.  if
что ты ещё приносишь деньги будет если
I earn enough money for one apartment, give me a
заработаю С горбом на одну квартиру дай
second one, I’ll earn money for a rented one, I’ll
вторую заработаю на съёмную буду её
rent it out, I’ll do some renovations there, I’ll live with grief
сдавать сделаю там ремонт С горем
in half and I’ll live slowly, and
пополам и буду потихоньку жить и
all I’m saying is that somewhere I said something
всё я что где-то что-то не так сказал
wrong, I said something wrong
что-то не так сказал
You also have cars besides apartments  I wanted to
Ты ещё машины ты кроме квартир хотел ещё
rent out more cars Tell me more about
машины сдавать в аренду Расскажи мне ещё
the mathematics of cars How much does a
математику автомобилей Сколько стоит
car cost And how much can you rent it out?
автомобиль И сколько в аренду его можно
RUB 1000
сдавать руб 1000 руб
a day, that
день то
is, the car will bring in
есть автомобиль будет приносить
000 a month And how much does this car cost
000 меся А сколько стоит этот
500, that is, the car costs four
500 то есть автомобиль стоит в в четыре
times less than a hut but brings in  half the
раза дешевле хаты но приносит в два раза
size of a hut It’s cool it turns out to be
меньше хаты Прикольно он получается в
twice as efficient, that is,
два раза эффективней то есть автомобиль
you have a car in a year and a half, then I’m talking about the World Cup, I’m
ты через полтора года тогда ото бьёшь я
talking about the World Cup, it makes a profit, it makes a profit
те о ЧМ говорю он прибыль приносит
for gasoline, for everything they pay
приносит за бензин за всего они платят
Yes, you have it Minus You have
Да у тебя есть Минус У тебя есть
consumables that are in the car Yes  you
расходники что в машине Да ты всё
change everything and then they are there in a terrible way
меняешь и дальше они там по-страшному
there are some who generally ride the suspension they
там есть такие вообще катаются подвеску
don’t spare at all different ones there are well
вообще не жалеют разные есть ну в
basically yes even if we take into account this
основном да если даже учесть этот
nuance with the consumption of materials the
нюанс с расходом материалов
machine
машины
consumes anyway It will be profitable
потребляемых всё равно Выгодно будет
wait for 500,000 you this Lada Yes you want to
подожди за 500000 ты эту Ладу Да хочешь
buy it too Yes  500,000 Volkswagen floor
тоже купить Да 500.000 Volkswagen пола
here you can buy a broken one in the garage,
тут можно купить разбитый в гараже его
pull it out on it and then put it up in
вытянуть на нём а потом выставить в
Yandex for a taxi ride on it, everything
Яндек такси на нём кататься всё
is fun, it’s already flattening you a little Let’s
прикольно тебя уже Немного плющит Давай
drink Yes, okay for ours Everyone for
выпьем Да нормально за наши Каждый за
their own country Come on, come on Kula kte Yes Don’t
свою страну Давай давай Кула кте Да Не
let Everyone drink for their own country  you
давай Каждый за свою страну выпи ты за
don’t drink for the country, it’s a sin Well, I drank the country,
страну не выпить это грех Ну я страну
I drank it. Let me smoke for the country. I’ll smoke for the country.
выпил выпил Давай поку я покурю за стра
I don’t want to drink like you. Do you
я покурю заст пить не хочу как ты У тебя
have anyone you know who died in the army? Yes,
есть кто-то из знакомых кто погиб на
half of my company, who’s half of my company with
сво Да пол роты моей кто пол моей роты с
whom I served  they all died And
которыми я служил они погибли все А за
why did they die
что они погибли
for Russia? Well, why
за Россию Ну в чём за
look for Russia, come on, so they weren’t
Россию смотри давай так они не
mobilized, I already have everything, a tractor driver can come to me,
мобилизованы у меня уже всё можно ко мне
oh
тракториста ой
tractor, speech therapists can be called to me,
трактори логопеды ко мне можно вызывать
in short,
короче
they weren’t
вот они не были
mobilized for the second time. They served at
мобилизованы вовторых Они служили на
their job
своей работе
when  I served with them, they remained under
когда я с ними служил они остались по
contract and continued to serve.
контракту дальше служить проходит
How many years passed? 5 years passed after that, they were
Сколько лет 5 лет прошло после это они
still there and worked, they were all called up by
так же там и работали их всех призвали
everyone who was under contract, everyone hop off and that’s
все кто по контракту все хоп поехали и
all, half at once, half after 2
всё что половину сразу половину через 2
years,
года
that’s all, half of my company is gone, that’s all
всё половина моей роты нет больше всё
bury everyone for the Motherland, all for the Motherland, for
всех похорони за Родину все за Родину за
working for the Motherland, he said something else,
работу за Родину хо м другое сказал в
what in what for the Motherland? What? Well, what was the goal of
чём в чём за Родину В чём Ну в чём цель
the Motherland?
Родины
Look, your side is being
была Смотри вот на твою сторону нападает
attacked. So, why are you not
нападает Так ну на ва Почему ты не
defending? Why are you stopping at yours?
защищаешь Почему ты по стоп на вашу на
your country wasn’t attacked That’s why they
вашу страну не напали Вот за что они
died, why they were left to die
погибли ради чего их кинули умирать
Explain to me the most important question, look
Объясни мне самый главный вопрос смотри
Another question Why they attacked your
Другой вопрос Почему напали на твою
country No, you’re not a cutoff, you answer for what
страну Нет ты не среза ты ответь за что
I am I’ll answer the question Dude, you’re not a
я те Отвечу Отвечу на вопрос Чувак ты не
cutoff, you want to translate Look  here
среза ты хочешь перевести Смотри вот
you are, you say half a company And so on
твои ты говоришь пол роты И так дальше
Yes, they are stupid for nothing for Putin, but it
Да они тупо ни за что за Путина да
turns out you can explain why they
получается можешь объяснить за что они
died for the Motherland and that’s all Well,
погибли за Родину матушку и всё Ну в чём
why for the Motherland they didn’t attack their homeland,
в чём за Родину на их его родину не
that’s why they got into someone else’s
нападали вот зачем они полезли в чуж
question  I stood there with them, maybe
спроси у них я там с ними стоял что ли
shoulder to shoulder or not, I’m not with them, well, what do you
плечо о плечо или нет я с ними не ну ты
think, what do you think, they
как считаешь ты как считаешь за Родину
died for the Motherland and that’s it. Well, I mean for the Motherland. Well,
погибли и всё Ну в смысле за Родину Ну
for what for the Motherland? A patriot from his country
за что за Родину Патриот с своей страны
or not, and what is it?  homeland is Putin,
или нет а что что такое родина это Путин
in short, this is Medvedev where is this Motherland
короче это Медведев где эта Родина У вас
What is your homeland Your native land And
что такое родина Твой родной край А
somewhere do you live Where were you born Well, they
где-то живёшь Где ты родился Ну они
were born in Ryazan So why did they
родились в Рязане Так почему они за
die for Ryazan somewhere near
Рязань погибли где-то под
Kharkov also in the army army Why
Харьковом также е в армии армия Почему
look at yours here  this is someone from Ryazan
смотри Твой вот это какой-то из Рязани
who died in Kharkov where is the
погиб Харьковом где там
Motherland where is the homeland he was
Родина где родина он
defending his country interestingly Stop
защищал интересно своей страны Всё стоп
stop he was defending some interests or
стоп то он защищал какие-то интересы или
he was howling for his homeland for his country I will
он за Родину выл за своей страны я те
repeat that what kind of interests the question is so
повторю вот а что за интересы вопрос так
what is this  the interests that he
что что это за интересы которые он
defended can you voice these interests of
защищал можешь озвучить эти интересы
interest no, I can’t voice you
интереса нет не могу тебя озвучить
because I don’t know these interests, so
потому что я интереса эти не знаю ну так
wait Well, it turns out they didn’t
подожди Ну как то есть они получается не
know what they were dying for, look, I’ll kill you,
знали за что умирают смотри перебью тебя
I’m sorry, you don’t care, look at you,
Извини тебе не вка смотри на тебя
someone attacked you, let’s say  you again
какой-то напал допустим ты ещё раз
Look, you want to run away again Answer the
Смотри ты ещё раз хочешь убежать Ответь
simple question yes What interests of
на простой вопрос да Какие интересы
their country are they defending here yes that
своей страны они сюда защищают да то
is And for example When our grandfathers In the forty-
есть А например Когда наши деды В сорок
first Yes Hitler attacked here it’s clear they were
первом Да напал Гитлер тут понятно они
defending from Hitler Yes why did yours
защищали от Гитлера Да от чего твой из
go from Ryazan to someone else’s  to defend the country
Рязани поехал в чужую страну защищать
What are the interests
Какие интересы
Explain the interest of your country in the World Cup,
Объясни в ЧМ интерес твоей страны вот
what is the interest they want resources to
Какой интерес они хотят ресурсы
seize people what they want Your country
захватить людей что хохочет Твоя страна
What are the interests so that Crimea is ours everything
Какие интересы м чтобы Крым был наш всё
And that is, and you were in Crimea by the way, yes you were,
А то есть а ты в Крыму был кстати да был
but you need to secure it understood secure And
но надо обезопасить понял обезопасить А
how exactly to
как именно
secure  Keep the aircraft a little further from
обезопасить Чуть подальше держать ВС от
Crimea because Crimea
Крыма потому Крым
will be paralyzed and everything will be like troops
парализован будет и всё как туда войска
will enter there from one place, you’re like yes There
зайдут с одного места ты как да Там мост
is a bridge there is a bridge at any time, it’s
есть мост в любой момент это понятное
understandable Yes, troops won’t go there
дело Да туда войска ники Не поступят
Crimea will immediately occupy everything There is no Crimea,
Крым сразу оккупирует всё Крыма нет
so we need
поэтому нужна
territory to Crimea so that  there was
территория до Крыма чтобы была
security about this. Why do you need
безопасность насчёт этого А зачем вам
Crimea at all?
вообще Крым
Well, you don’t want to relax there, for example
Ну ты там не хочешь отдохнуть к примеру
Toda, you can go from this way. But before,
Тода можешь поехать от так А раньше вот
when Crimea was not captured by Russia, you
когда Крым был не захвачен Россией можно
could relax, what’s the problem with going
было отдыхать в чём проблема поехать
to Crimea to relax if it’s
отдохнуть в Крым если он
Ukraine, it’s beautiful there, but now it’s cold, of
Украина там красиво ну сейчас холодно
course  in the summer Go have a nice rest, don’t
конечно летом Съезди отдохни красиво не
look like that, for example, to go to
так смотри например чтобы поехать в
Turkey to Egypt to Croatia to Greece you
Турцию в Египет в Хорватию в Грецию их
don’t need to capture them You can go and
не надо захватить Можно поехать и
relax Why to go to Crimea you
отдыхать Почему чтобы поехать в Крым
need to
нужно его
capture it and Crimea was originally I
захватить а Крым изначально был
don’t know Well, it was already in Ukraine yes
не знаю Ну так он уже Украины был да
Why That’s why
Зачем Вот зачем его
capture it Why don’t you know
захватывать Поче ты не знае
Greek Greek Yes, having become Greek
греческий греческий Да дав греческим
initially he became Russian, it turns out
изначально он стал русским получается
when he became
когда он стал
Russian in what year Well, in what year did you
русским в чем году Ну вот в че вы его
capture him Yes, and under occupation,
захватили Да и под оккупацией во
I have a question for you, too, you don’t
п у меня к тебе вопрос тоже тебе не
like that they occupied Crimea, wait
нравится что оккупировали Крым подожди я
I want to figure it out I don’t like it I’m a
я хочу разобраться мне нет нравится н я
simple person I don’t understand
вот простой человек Я не разбираюсь в
politics I’m interested in the Russians’ opinion
политике мне интересно у Россиян мнение
Why did you seize Crimea to go
Для чего вы захватили Крым чтобы ехать
there on vacation I work for the hardware What kind of
туда отдыхать Я работаю на желез Какая
politics Why did you seize Crimea Why did
политика Для чего вы захватили Крым Для
Crimea ask me Volodya  Volo, well, you
рым меня спра Спроси у Володи воло ну ты
support the seizure of Crimea. So you
ж поддерживаешь захват Крыма Значит ты
know why it was captured. Well,
знаешь зачем его захватывали Ну там
I liked it there to relax there. It’s beautiful,
отдыхать мне там понравилось там красиво
that is, it was captured in order to have a
то есть его захватили для того чтобы там
great vacation there. I won’t say that there’s
классно отдыхать этого не скажу что Крым
some Crimea over there, too, on the Black Sea
какой-то вон тоже на Черноморском
coast, where you can relax and
побережье там ку которых можно отх и
also too
также слишком
much
сильно
advertised
разрекламированные
why for Because you support
зачем за Потому что ты поддерживаешь Это
I’m asking why you support the
я спрашиваю почему ты поддерживаешь
seizure of
захват
Crimea why are you asking me It’s
Крыма почему ты у меня спрашиваешь Это
because I’m talking to you it must mean
потому что я с тобой говорю нужно значит
Why did you give him away why did he
А почему вы его отдали почему он без
leave without a war as without a war the war was
войны ушёл как без войны война была
just a war  continues now
просто вот война продолжается сейчас
minus the year they attacked Explain why you
вычетом году напали Объясни почему вы
captured him Why you just gave him away and that’s it
его захватили Почему просто отдали и всё
and explain why you captured him Why do you need
и объясни почему вы его захватили Зачем
him Why was Ukraine silent Wait,
он вам Почему молчала Украина Подожди
look, there’s Okay, a very important
смотри есть Ладно очень важное
announcement, a minute, a minute, a very important
объявление минутку минутку очень важное
announcement, look, ready for the answer, ready to
объявление смотри готовы ответ готовы
listen,
слушать л
here, let’s just make it short  that's all
сюда давай просто его короче это уже всё
he has
у него
squirrel Why cream because it
белка Зачем крем потому что в нём
rests because it advertises
отдыхает потому что он разрекламировать
what's in their heads This is
что у них в головах Вот
someone sitting there in Ryazan Yes in
это сидит какой-то там в Рязани Да в
grandma's barn drinking with a friend
бабушкином сарае бухает с другом
telling a fable how he counts
рассказывает басне как он там считать
apartments there how he will buy and  to hand
квартиры как он будет покупать и сдавать
over Crimea to him Crimea to him
но ему Крым Крым ему
Crimea comment write to th Instagram I don’t
Крым комент пись на й Instagram Я не
know why you are there Why are you
знаю для чого це тоб Для чего тоб там
marveling at the office and for you one or two or
дивитись на офес а для тебе один два або
three clicks and you are three to me and I will be
три клика а ты тримае мене и я буду кау
in me there A bunch of fouls and in me  be
в мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
cool mood to be robiti but cool video
класний настрий щоб робити но крут вдео
message on th Instagram Popik here's takva
пись на й Instagram Попик вот таква
with
с